Hey, this area's restricted.
Oh, hi.
Yeah, I know.
They call me down here.
Some of this wiring got screwed up.
Nobody called it down to me.
I'm gonna have to see a work order.
Yeah, just a second.
There you are.
Nothing personal.
Well, I guess that wraps it up.
Good work, everybody.
Marty, I couldn't be happier with the way this worked out.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Oh, hold up.
Whoa.
Gee, thanks.
Watch the light.
Thanks for pushing that, Bob.
The light's on, but you never know.
It really might be broken.
Shut up.
I didn't remember, honey.
I promise.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what you're thinking.
Why don't you forget about it?
Unbelievable.
You come back.
You don't want to think too much.
APPLAUSE
Wow.
Look, see.
That yellowing thing is one of his talented experts.
V movie.
That blue thing also Red Bull.
That means one of his opponents.
Thank you.
I'll give you that at-ちょっとvänd, ¶ ´ ¶
Hold on.
Hold on to your Typhus.
Just a minute.
Oh.
2020.
What button did you push?
421, David.
We're checking in.
David, you're suspected.
All responding David team units, respond to rock bottom.
All right.
We're checking in.
Good night.
Mr. Bagwell, make sure these other elevators remain locked down and empty.
Yes, sir.
Now, there's no other way.
No doors.
No other way in or out except through access panels.
Is that correct?
Yes, sir.
We have here 13 passengers in an express elevator.
Below floor 30.
Bombs already taken out cables.
Bomber wants $3 million or he blows the emergency brakes.
What's our clock?
He gave one hour.
That leaves us 23 minutes exactly.
Anything else that will keep this elevator from falling?
The basement.
The city would like to avoid that event, Officer Traven.
We can't just unload the passengers.
This is an express elevator, gentlemen.
The only way in or out is through access panels.
Also wired the hatch to trigger the bomb, which seats him in the crazy but not stupid
section.
So Harry volunteers to examine the device.
Yeah, right.
Fine.
The two of you check it out.
The nearest access panel's on the 32nd floor in the lobby.
I want reports only.
We're in a holding pattern.
Worthy Briggs, I want you to secure the base area.
No one in or out.
Everyone else, I want you to be firm.
Building evac.
Move!
Looks like we're walking.
Harry, watch your step.
29.
All the way down to the lobby.
Come on, folks.
30.
31.
32.
Hello?
II
Please! Get us out of here!
Who's up there? Who's up there? What's going on?
Ladies and gentlemen, this is the LAPD!
Thank God.
What are you doing up there?
I'm just trying to get some air.
There has been an elevator malfunction, so just relax.
Hey, come on! What are you guys waiting for?
We'll have you out of there as soon as possible.
Am I lying?
How come they send cops here? Shouldn't they send repair guys?
Makes sense.
I'm not sure.
I don't know.
Shouldn't they send repair guys?
Makes sense.
What do you think?
You're the expert. I just work here.
Looks pretty solid.
Anyone we know?
I don't recognize the work, but he's a pro.
He's got me close.
I don't like it.
What's to like?
Max said we hold, so we hold.
All right, pop quiz.
Airport, gunman with one hostage.
He's using her for cover.
He's almost to a plane.
You're 100 feet away.
Jack.
Shoot the hostage.
What?
Take her out of the equation.
Go for the good wound and he can't get to the plane with her.
Clear shot.
You're deeply nuts. You know that?
Shoot the hostage.
Harry, this is wrong.
He's gonna blow it anyway.
Why?
I don't know. Gut feeling.
Right now Mac outranks your gut, so he's set.
This is taking way too long.
How much you think that elevator weighs?
Jack, come on.
Maybe we can do something about those hostages.
We're not gonna shoot them, right?
Hey, where you going? What's going on?
Don't go.
Don't leave us here.
Go, go, go.
No, we just take them out of the equation.
You sure it'll hold?
It'll hold.
Six minutes.
I can't get any more time.
He's not talking.
I need the goddamn money now.
You're gonna get me.
Tell me again, Harry.
Why did I take this job?
Oh, come on. 30 more years of this, you get a tiny pension of a cheap, bold watch.
Cool.
Hold.
I'm gonna go.
God, it's hot in here.
There's no air.
I can't breathe.
Don't fuck with daddy.
Grab her hand.
Usually they fall down now.
It's early.
Bitch, it's early.
I'm gonna go.
Mac, we need more help up here.
Now.
Oh, please.
I wanna die.
Please save us.
Help me.
Save me.
Open the door.
It's okay, Mac.
We'll get you out.
Give me your hand.
It's okay. Give me your hand.
Pull me through.
Watch your head.
Take it easy.
You're fine.
Take her.
Okay, let's go next.
Thank you.
What the hell is all this?
Help us, hurry.
Hurry up.
Let's go.
Come on.
Help me.
Watch your head.
Come on, lady. Come on.
Around the hip.
No.
There's too many people around.
Come on. Come on. Let's go.
It's going to fall.
Just take one step.
Reach out and take my hand.
Come on.
Oh, God.
Don't let go of me.
You're okay.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
Was it good for you?
It was great, friend.
What was it for you, honey?
Elevator dropped. Oh, good.
That's good to know.
Is your watch slow?
No, no, no. He jumped the gun.
He's got three minutes left.
Why does he do that?
He's losing his three million.
I don't know. Maybe he couldn't hold his wad long enough.
It's a common problem among middle-aged men.
So I'm told.
He's here.
He could have blown that thing from Pacoima.
No.
He knew we were up to something.
He's close by.
He's got a corner himself in a building we evacuated anyway.
Come on.
He'd want to be here, but he'd want to stay mobile, right?
The elevators.
Passenger cars were stopped.
They checked them out.
What about the freight elevators?
They're all gone.
Will the mystery guest please sign in?
What?
Damn it.
Get to the side!
Get your ass up.
Damn it.
I don't suppose anybody would give me three million just for you.
Hold it.
Pop quiz, hot shot.
Terrace holding a police host.
He's got enough dynamite strapped to his chest to blow a building in half.
Now what do you do?
There's going to be 50 cops waiting for you in the basement.
Standard flanking the one, right?
Well, maybe we'll get off on the third floor.
I want location on those goddamn shots.
Briggs, where's Jack and Harry?
Lieutenant, we've got movement on the freight elevator.
It's on three.
Let's move.
Underline.
This day has been real disappointing, I don't mind saying.
Why, because you didn't get to kill everyone?
There will come a time, boy,
when you'll wish you never met me.
Mister, I'm already there.
See, I'm in charge here.
I drop this stick,
and they pick your friend up with a sponge.
Are you ready to die, friend?
Fuck you.
Oh, in 200 years,
we've come from my regret,
but I have one life to give for my country to
fuck you.
Go ahead, drop the stick. Do it.
Shut up, Harry.
Oh, we've got all the balls in the world right here, man.
Get up! You've got nowhere to go!
Shoot the hostage.
Say goodbye, Harry.
Ow!
You fuck.
Briggs!
Give it up! You're out of options!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Through dedication and bravery,
these next two offices
affected the rescue of 13 citizens
of this city.
And thanks to them, the only life
taken by the terrorist bomb was his own.
You shot me. I can't
believe it. I'm giving you a medal
for shooting me, you little prick.
Harry,
you told me to.
Officer Harry Temple.
Officer Jack Trapp.
Way to go, Jack! Way to go!
There we go. There we go.
Oh, beautiful.
So is to me. I can't even feel good about myself.
Hey, Sandy!
Here we go!
So how we do... Oh, whoa, whoa!
I need a beer, boy!
Here we go. All right.
And here
is to Harry.
For his quick thinking,
for his grace
under pressure, and for his brave
and selfless act.
Here, here, here.
And
to Jack for shooting
Harry. Something
we've all wanted to do for a very long
time.
Okay,
no, no, here it is. Here it is.
Here's to you guys for doing your job
and for not getting
dead. Muzzle time.
Muzzle time.
We are the two luckiest guys
in the world. You know that? We got the
bad guy and we didn't lose any
civilians. Yeah, we're good. No.
You were lucky. No, we were lucky.
You better understand it.
We were dealing with a total
psycho. You know, this guy could
have blown us up at any time.
Phew. And I got a
bullet in me.
Six inches off the mark and they're
giving the medal to my wife.
Harry, come on, man.
We won. We got him.
Do you listen?
Do you ever? Because I am not
going to be around to back you up.
So you better start thinking.
Guts will
get you so far and then they'll get you killed.
Luck runs out
sooner or later. Right, Chief?
Right.
I'm going to go home, have some
sex.
Harry, you're going to go
home and puke. Yeah, well,
that'll be fun too.
Come on, you kid.
Hey, Jack.
Saw you on TV.
Congratulations. Thanks, Bob.
Yeah, you look fat. Be easy on him, Bob.
The boy was up late last night partying.
Oh, a wild party, huh? Yeah, well, I don't
remember that well.
It could have been too great. I woke up alone.
Yeah? Well, you know, the last time I partied
like that, I woke up married.
Huh, Vinnie?
I'm sorry.
I woke up married. Huh, Vinnie?
Hey, Jack, you forgot
your marker. Have a good one,
Bob. Thanks, Jack. Take care, huh?
Thanks.
See you tomorrow.
What do you think, Jack?
You think if you pick up all
the bus drivers' teeth,
they'll give you another medal?
Jesus.
You think I wouldn't have been prepared?
Two years I spent
setting up that elevator job.
Two years I invested myself in it.
You couldn't understand
the cost of the elevator.
You couldn't understand the cost of the elevator.
You couldn't understand the kind of commitment
that I have.
You're wearing a man's life's work,
and you think you can walk away.
You've got blinders on to the world.
But I got your attention now, didn't I, Jack?
Why didn't you just come after me?
No, this is about me.
This is about my money.
This is about money to me,
which I will collect.
$3.7 million.
It's my nest egg, Jack.
At my age, you've got to think ahead.
When I find you...
Top quiz, hotshot.
There's a bomb on a bus.
Once the bus goes 50 miles an hour,
the bomb is armed.
If it drops below 50,
it blows up.
What do you do?
I'd want to know what bus it was.
You think I'm going to tell you that?
Yes.
Very good.
There are rules, Jack,
and I want you to get this right.
No one goes off the bus.
You try to take any passengers off the bus,
I will detonate it.
I want my money by 11 a.m.
We can't pull that kind of money in time.
Focus, Jack.
Your concern is the bus.
Don't try to call.
The radio's down.
Now, the number of the bus is 25-25.
It's running downtown from Venice.
It's at the corner of Ocean Park.
Sam!
Tell him to stop!
Excuse me, coming through!
Sam!
This ain't a bus stop!
Get rid of your butt, Annie.
Okay, it's gone.
You are a good kind man.
One day, people will write songs about you.
Hi.
First time in L.A.
Oh, no, I live here.
No, I mean mine.
Oh, that's just funny.
You heard me wrong.
No, I'm sightseeing.
Oh, really?
Yeah, I hate to use the word tourist,
but it's not like I can hide it.
Not really.
Oh, jeez.
You know, it took me three hours
just to get here from the airport.
I'm so lost.
L.A. is one large place.
Of course, you live here, you probably don't notice.
I'm such a yokel.
There, I said it.
You know what? I got gum on my seat.
Gum.
Excuse me.
Morning. Hi.
Hey, watch out!
Hey.
I just couldn't handle the freeways anymore.
I got so tense.
That's intense.
This way I can just relax all the way to work.
Yeah, well, I love my car.
I miss my car.
Woo!
Beep!
Oh, God.
Look at that.
Hey, Sam?
Shit.
Sam!
What?
Why don't you just drive over these people or something?
Don't spit on my bus, Annie.
Such a mess.
Woo!
Stop!
Open up!
Get off the road, man.
This ain't no bus stop.
I really want to get on the bus.
Open up!
Stop!
No, Sam, don't go on!
LAPD!
I can't hear you.
Stop this bus!
What?
LAPD!
Stop the bus!
Stop!
LAPD!
Get out of the car!
I'm telling you, this is my car.
I own this car.
It's not stolen.
It is now.
Move over.
Fuck!
You scratch this puppy, and me and you are gonna have words.
You understand?
Okay, look, man, we don't have to go so fast, all right?
Just slow down a little bit, all right?
Just slow down.
Oh, shit!
Come on, man.
Don't tear up my car, all right?
Okay, okay.
Just slow down just a bit, all right?
We don't have to go so fast, do we?
I mean, we don't have to go so...
That was a nice move, man.
I'm sorry, man.
Shit, shit, shit, shit!
Move!
You can do a slow down.
Come on!
Oh, shit!
Go!
Move!
Is that that guy?
Man, sure has a hard on for this bus.
Fuck!
Hey!
I'm a cop!
What?
LAPD!
There's a bomb on your bus!
There's a...
What?
Fuck!
There's a bomb on your bus!
Watch the road!
Grab that, William.
I want you to ride on it.
I want you to ride on the back bomb on bus.
Ride it, ride it, ride it!
Watch the road!
Oh, shit!
No!
Don't slow down!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Speed up!
Open your doors!
Open the doors!
50!
Stay in bus 50!
All right?
478,000 asked for Detective Harry Temple.
Harry Temple.
Harry.
Harry, it's Jack.
You better not be calling in sick, or I'll drag my ass out of...
Harry, he's alive!
What?
The bomber!
He's back!
He hit one in Venice already.
Fire chief said there's nothing left.
Temple!
We just got a ransom demand from your dead terrorist.
Says he's rigged the city bus.
Where's Jack?
Where do you think?
I gotta get on that bus.
You gotta get him.
Yeah, yeah, you get on the bus.
Drive straight!
Stay in this lane!
Watch your own.
Wait a minute, what are you doing?
Are you insured?
Yeah, why?
No, no!
Broke my... my door!
Sir, I need to take your phone.
Take the phone!
Take the wheel.
Wheel?
What?
W-w-w-w-shit!
W-w-w-shit!
Drive straight!
Ah!
Oh shit!
This guy's out of his mind.
Okay, we gotta stay above the feet.
Excuse me, are you out of your mind?
Whatever it takes.
Hello?
Everybody, I'm Jack Trav in LAPD.
We have a slight situation on the bus here.
Ma'am, if you'll please sit down and do it this morning.
No, I won't sit in.
You're scaring the shit out of these people.
Ma'am, please!
If everybody will stay in your seats and remain calm,
we should be able to defuse the problem.
So sit tight and...
Get away from me!
I don't know you, man.
I'm not here for you.
Let's not do this.
Stop the bus!
He can't.
Shut up!
Stop the bus!
Stop him!
Look, look, listen!
Look, I'm putting my gun away, okay?
Okay?
Now listen.
I don't care about your crime.
Whatever you did, I'm sure that you're sorry.
So it's cool now.
It's over.
I'm not a cop right now.
See?
We're just two cool guys just hanging out.
Get off!
Stop!
Ma'am!
I've got the wheel.
I've got it, I've got it, I've got it.
Sam, oh God, Sam.
Sam, come on.
Sam, I ain't got both hands left.
Hold on!
Sam, get your foot.
Sam, get your foot off the pedal.
We've got to stop this thing.
No!
Don't!
Stay above 50!
But Sam's not showing!
We've got to get him off!
You slow down and this bus will explode!
There is a bomb.
There is a bomb on this bus.
If we slow down, it'll blow.
If anyone tries to get off, it'll explode.
Bullshit!
Yeah, there's a bomb.
Some funny joke, man.
Are we going to have a problem now?
He's bleeding so much, I don't know what to do.
There's so much blood.
Put pressure front and back.
Keep his legs up and put this under his head.
Hold on.
Sam, lift your hand.
Miss, can you handle this bus?
Sure, it's just like driving a really big pinto.
I need to know.
Can you handle this bus?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Just tell me what the plan is.
Is there a plan?
Just for you to drive.
We're okay for now.
Just keep us above 50.
Good plan.
So you're a cop, right?
That's right.
Well, I should probably tell you that I'm taking the bus
because I have my driver's license revoked.
What for?
Speeding.
Harry, we're on our way to the chopper.
If anything changes, let us know.
Anything we haven't seen should be in here.
What's wrong with the driver?
That at least one car, a Jaguar,
has been driven off the road by the speeding bus.
It appears to be somewhere in the middle of the road.
It began picking up speed, swerving,
and hasn't slowed down since.
Minutes ago, a Los Angeles police officer
boarded the bus by jumping onto it
from a moving car.
The bus was moving at a speed of about 50 miles an hour.
It's been driving off the road by the speed of one car.
Oh, with that BU-J.
The bus was moving at a speed of about 50 miles an hour.
Where do we start?
Check the speedometers.
Has it been fucked with or loosened or any wires?
Any wires or anything?
Excuse me, ma'am.
No, it's clean.
All right, that's going to be under the bus.
Probably going to break into one of the axes.
I can't get under the bus right now, Harry.
It's kind of in motion.
Excuse me.
Hold on.
Yes.
Access panel.
In the floor.
Underneath you.
OK.
All right, Harry, we're in.
Passenger relay.
Sir, take this.
I want you to tell them what I see.
OK.
We got a wad.
Pretty big.
There's a pretty big wad.
Brass fittings?
Brass fittings.
I think I can reach the circuit wire.
He can reach the circuit wire.
No, no, no, no.
Don't, don't, don't.
That's a decoy.
Classic.
That's your classic decoy.
What else?
Hold on.
Fuck me.
Oh, darn.
Harry, there's enough C4 on this thing
to put a hole in the world.
OK, all right, just stay calm.
What else?
Three triggers, one on the axle.
I can't really see.
A cellular remote.
Officer.
And a timer running off a wristwatch.
A watch?
What kind of watch?
Gold.
Gold band, fairly cheesy.
Officer.
What's on your mind, Harry?
Shit.
What do I do?
Officer!
Which way?
Get on the shoulder.
OK.
Watch it.
Stay on or get off.
Off.
Hold on.
Oh, my god.
Keep going.
It's red.
Go.
What?
Ow.
This is much better.
City streets.
The bus is on Western, heading in a southbound direction.
Now, when the bus did exit here, it had a couple of close calls.
Yeah, yeah.
All right.
I don't get it.
Watch is a shitty timer.
Why use it?
What's he saying?
Lots of people have watches here.
This guy has no ammo.
A bomber falls in love with one kind of bomb, and they're very monogamous.
This guy uses C4, dynamite, different trigger every time, and now he throws in this watch.
He's an encyclopedia of bombs.
He knows every kind.
Yeah, and everything we do to dismantle it.
Wait a minute.
I want to look at the files for the last 10 years.
We did the mug shots already.
It's not going to help.
No.
I want to look at cops.
Come on.
Let's go.
Yeah, Mac, where have you been?
I had to bail on the freeway.
We're in the city.
I can see you.
Just keep going straight.
I'm going to try to clear the roads for you.
Just stay on line.
Shit.
Jesus.
God, no.
Go back.
Sorry.
Oh my God.
Oh, jeez.
Stay out of my way.
Ma'am, up to the right.
Okay, okay, okay.
I see it.
Mac, Mac, you've got to get me out of here.
Oh, God.
A few more blocks.
You're going to come up to a soft turn.
Right.
Then hold straight.
I've got some units waiting for you there.
They're going to lead you to the 105 freeway.
It's not in use.
It'll be empty.
You'll be totally clear.
Got it.
In a few blocks, we'll take a soft turn to the right.
Okay.
Wait a minute.
Wait.
Eskort to where?
Where do we get an Eskort?
Look out.
Oh, God.
What?
Oh, jeez.
Oh, my God.
Cans.
I can see the cans.
Is that it?
Oh, my God.
There was no bin.
It was full of cans.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Oh, my God.
Can't.
There is someone up here.
Me?
Me.
Look.
There is someone up here.
Oh, my God.
Me.
Look.
There is someone up here.
We're going to getaway.
Where's he in school? Where's he in school?
Mac, we're bombed.
I'll get you out, Jack.
All right, listen. We got an entrance coming up, Jack.
It's gonna be a real ugly turn, though.
How ugly?
What's ugly?
We got a hard right coming up at the construction site.
This should be it.
That is a dead end.
There's a turn.
I can't make that turn.
You can make it.
No.
You keep left. You keep left. You make it blind.
Oh, God, we're gonna tip over. We're gonna tip over.
You're right. We're gonna tip over.
Everyone on this side of the bus, now!
All right.
On this side of the bus, as far as you can, please.
Hold on!
Over here. Over here. As far as you can. Now!
That's it.
Mac, you better clear this side out.
Please, sir!
Everybody, hold on!
This side of the bus!
Hold on!
Hold on! Here we go! Here we go!
Here we go!
Oh, my God!
Oh, God, is everybody all right?
Yes!
Oh, my God!
Take me to that interchange at the 105.
Oh, my God, we might have died.
I can't think.
It's okay.
If you need two, you go right ahead and vomit.
Go right there.
Go!
Come on, go!
All right.
Get rid of that scoundrel in England.
Place him with Webby.
Okay.
Go away!
I want air units overhead.
No obstructions in the freeway.
We have a window here. I want to make sure it stays open.
Right!
Here, sir!
This gentleman's gonna drive you down.
Shoot.
Could you do me a favor and hold the wheel for me for a second?
Hold the wheel.
Thank you.
Ma'am, you did very well.
Actually, you were incredible.
I've never seen driving like that.
Annie.
What?
It's my name, Annie.
Annie.
Is it supposed to ma'am?
Okay.
So...
Why is all this happening?
I mean, what do we do?
You bomb the guy's country or something?
No, it's just the guy wants money.
I don't buy that.
It's not a very good way to make money.
So, um...
What is this guy's deal?
A while back he held some people for ransom.
Went sour, now he's a little pissed at me.
What does that have to do with us?
Nothing.
It's a game.
If he gets the money, he wins.
If the bus blows up, he wins.
What if you win?
Then tomorrow we'll play another one.
But I'm not available to drive tomorrow.
Busy.
We got no match for that description.
No one's lost a thumb for at least the last ten years.
He could be from anywhere.
I can't access all that.
Forget the files.
I want you to start going through the pension fund.
This guy's drawn disability.
He may not be LAPD, but he's living here now.
I want pictures.
I've seen this asshole.
Hey!
Hey, Mark.
Let's get these passengers off the bus.
We can't do it, sir.
There's no time for any stunts, Traven.
We gotta get these people out of harm's way.
I got orders.
If we move these people, he'll see.
Remember, crazy, not stupid.
All right, look, Harry's trying to find out who this guy is.
We think maybe he's a cop.
Lieutenant, it's him.
He wants to talk to Jack.
He's on the line for you.
Okay, give him the number.
Give him the number!
How's he doing?
Bleeding his last foot.
Are they going to help us?
Sure they are. They're the police.
Hey, your taxes are paying their salary.
If we die, they gotta take a pay cut.
I mean, you know...
Yeah?
I think we have trust.
But it looks on TV like you're trying to get those passengers off the bus.
Look, you gotta let me have one.
Now, we went over the rules as an act of faith.
We have an injured man here.
The driver's been shot.
Jack, now tell me that you haven't been shooting the passengers.
I thought it was customary for a police officer to, you know, shoot the bad guys, huh?
This man has no time.
No one gets off.
It'll grease the wheels with the money, man, if you show a little charity.
There's still going to be plenty of us to kill.
Okay, son, you can try and unload the driver.
You tell that wildcat behind the wheel not to slow down, though.
He won't even get a chance to bleed to death.
And, Jack, don't slip.
He's letting us unload the driver.
No one!
Get us closer!
We're trying to get the bus driver off!
We're gonna get the driver off.
Just him?
For now.
Gigantor.
Ortiz.
I'm gonna need your help.
Okay.
Yeah, I need you to pass him to me.
You have to keep him straight.
You're, I think, the Wundelterre.
What about the rest of us?
Hey, hey, hey!
Lady!
Guys, I'm gonna cut your hair.
I can't stay!
How you feeling?
Like a pinched shot.
Thank you, Sam.
Okay, Andy.
Drive straight!
Keep him straight!
Okay, we'll get as close as you can, okay?
All right.
Closer!
A little closer, Andy!
Andy, a little closer!
Okay!
Okay, how's this?
Sorry!
Okay, Andy, no problem.
Let's try one more time.
A little more!
Okay, okay!
Right there!
Steady!
Hold on steady!
Got him!
All right.
I'm all right, thanks.
Oh my God.
Yes!
Hey!
He's gonna be okay.
Come on!
Come on, lady, give me your hand!
I have to, Andy.
No, Helen!
No!
Helen, no!
Come on, right there!
No!
God damn it, Mac!
We gotta get those fucking choppers out of here!
Was driving the bus.
I couldn't tell how old...
An explosion!
Some kind of an explosion.
The bus hasn't exploded, but...
Oh my God.
A woman caught in the blast fell.
She was pulled under the wheels.
This is terrible.
Interactive TV, Jack.
Wave of the future.
Ha ha ha!
Huh?
I can't be here.
I can't, you know...
This is the wrong bus.
I mean, for me to...
I can't die here.
Hey, shut up, man.
I got a wife.
Oh, you do?
Hey!
So if you have a wife and I don't, does that mean I'm expendable?
Hey, what are you talking about, man?
The guy's just talking me crazy.
It gets on my nerves.
It gets on everybody's nerves.
Oh, yeah?
Well, I think I have the right to be a little bit upset.
What are you staring at, anyway, man?
After all the weepers.
Hold your nose in.
Why don't you just let everybody die in peace, if that's what's gonna happen?
I'm sure you're a really tough guy, huh?
You're really tough, huh, Jack?
Why don't we just step outside?
Hey!
How are you doing?
You all right?
Mm-mm.
What can I do?
When that bomb went off?
I know.
I thought that was it.
I thought that was a bomb.
And I was dead.
And then when I saw her body fall under the bus, it was like...
You were glad you were still alive?
Mm-hmm.
I was.
I'm so sorry.
Don't be.
You should be glad.
We all are.
Doesn't mean you don't care.
I know, but she was so scared.
She was scared.
She was a nice lady who didn't deserve to get killed.
But Annie, if she'd gotten off, it would have killed us all.
He's the asshole, Annie.
The guy who put us here.
Remember that, okay?
Big asshole.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
He's sure.
Well, how far?
Sir, we have a serious problem.
What?
This freeway isn't finished.
What are you talking about?
The aerial unit got it about three miles ahead.
There's a section missing.
But it's on the map. It's finished on the goddamn map.
I guess they fell behind.
Fuck. You're fired. Everybody's fucking fired.
Get me closer.
Hey, get closer. Watch him in the mirror.
Jack!
How big is the section?
50 feet, at least.
There's a gap in the road up ahead. It's big.
You're kidding. How big?
50 feet.
Jack. What?
We've got to get these people off the bus somehow.
You know I can.
What did he say? Jack?
Jack! What did he say?
What did he say?
What's the matter?
There's a gap in the freeway.
What? What do you mean?
How big is a gap?
50 feet. A couple of miles ahead.
This is crazy.
What?
Jesus.
Jack, what if I shift into neutral and just keep the engine revving?
No, you'd have taught him that.
What then? What? What?
What? Jack?
Floor it.
What?
Floor it. It's an interchange. There might be an incline. Floor it.
Fine.
Everybody hold on to your seats or whatever you can.
When we hit the gap, heads down.
That's it? That's it?
That's all we can do.
Let's put these underneath your seat, all right?
Put your bags underneath the seat.
Hey, I didn't mean to shoot the guy.
Hold on.
Is this really going to work?
Jack!
Yeah?
Jack.
Oh, God.
Come on!
Everybody hold on!
Oh, baby.
Jack.
Shit!
Oh, my God!
We made it!
Yes!
We are way out of control!
We made it!
You okay? Yeah.
All right! Go on! Let's go!
Is everybody okay? Yes!
Whoa!
We made it!
We made it.
You're the man! You are the man!
Thank you. Thank you, man.
Goddamn! Yes!
Thank you, Mr. Collins. Yeah, what was it?
Watch the road.
You shouldn't have been a pilot. No.
Get off. What? Get off this.
Now, now. Get off this.
In there.
Where? Right here? Yeah.
Right here? Yeah.
Hey, hey, hey! Stop!
He's just entered the airport.
The airport? There's thousands of people there.
That's my boy Jack. We should be able to circle the runways and buy some time.
The choppers can't fly in there with restricted airspace.
He's headed for the end of the field.
We're going to have to go to the rectangle and emergency runway.
Yeah, let's hope it's built. Let's move!
We're at the airport.
Yeah. So?
I already seen the airport.
Yeah.
Very, very exciting, Jack.
Some close calls, huh?
But you've done all right for yourself.
What do you want? I want money, Jack.
I wish I had some loftier purpose, but...
I'm sorry.
I'm afraid in the end it's just the money, Jack.
I would like large non-sequential bills in two clear plastic bags unmarked.
Can you remember all that?
What are you telling me for?
Because I want you to help me to get it before it gets too late.
I hate negotiators, Jack. They talk to you like they're your best friend and they don't even know you.
Why are they messing with me, huh?
I'm not doing this for fun!
Aren't you?
Oh, that's unfair, Jack. You don't know how I feel about this.
You don't even know me.
I know you want a shitload of money you didn't earn.
Oh, I earned it. I spent my life earning it.
I got a medal too, Jack. A medal and a pink slip and a sorry about your hand.
You have to let me off.
Oh, no. That's not good.
I need to talk to these people face to face. They think you're bullshit.
They don't think that.
Look, you want the money. I don't want anyone else to die. Let me get on the ground.
Just me. That's not against the rules.
All right. I want you back real fast.
Fine.
Jack, nothing tricky now. You know that I'm on top of you.
Do not attempt to grow a brain.
...it could encourage other terrorists to try and pull off another stunt.
So I guess there's a plan now?
Could be.
Yeah?
He's letting me off.
What?
Just keep circling. You'll be fine.
Everybody, sit tight. I'm getting off for a minute.
Do you think that's a good idea?
It'll be okay. What, are you just gonna leave us here?
I would.
Don't worry. I won't go far.
Hey. Don't forget about us.
The choppers are gone, Jack. Let's dump the passengers now.
No way. He's ready for that.
How is that possible?
I don't know how, Mac. I just know he is.
There's been a step ahead every time. If we unload, he'll take them out, I guarantee.
So where does that put us?
I have to try and dismantle that bomb.
...an incredible ride from the 10th Freeway to the East of Los Angeles and the 105th Freeway.
This Santa Monica bus has ended up here at Los Angeles International Airport circling the runway.
I'm telling you, Henny, he's somewhere jerking off.
He didn't have to get on the bus in the first place, Ortiz.
Hey, get your ass behind the yellow line.
What is that?
I have no idea.
We won't be able to hold this thing steady for very long.
I just need a few minutes. If I can't do it by then, I can't do it at all.
Harry, you with me?
Yeah. You be careful, Jack.
What's he doing?
Oh my God, he is insane.
Okay, Jack, this is it. Don't get dead.
This is not a very good plan.
Have faith, sister.
Oh, Christ.
Just keep it steady.
Oh, thank you for the tip, Ortiz.
This guy is nuts.
Okay, we're gonna have to try to bypass the remote current with the battery.
Can you find the tripwire for the remote?
I don't know. I've got a few choices here.
Black and red?
And green.
Okay.
All right, I'm gonna guess he's not gonna go with standard copper for the remote.
That'd be too weak. I'd use a fiber alloy.
Jack, I need you to look at the wire.
Harry, it's covered.
Yeah, I know. You're gonna have to cut off the sheath.
But don't cut the wire.
Right.
You fucking pig!
Shit!
Bullseye!
Great.
Okay, I want you to clip on the battery and then run it to the lead wire.
Copy.
I can't bypass it. It'll fire!
Oh, shit. It's a collapsible circuit.
Howard Payne, Atlanta PD bomb squad.
Retired in Sun Valley in 1989 when a small charge left him with fingers numbering nine.
That's our scumbag!
We got him, Jack. We found him.
We can get to his place in 15 minutes.
Great. Jack, I want you to get out of there and sit tight.
We're gonna go after the sword.
Okay.
Wait for me.
Mac, get me out of here!
Somebody go to the back and check to see if he came out the back. Go!
Can you see him?
He's not behind us!
What?
He's not back here!
Oh, my God, oh, my God, oh, my God. Go, go, go, go, go. Lay down and look under the bus and see if you can see him down there.
Can you see him?
No!
You don't see him, like, by the back? Behind the tires or something? Look, down there something?
I can't see him!
Are you sure?
I can't see him.
I can't see him!
You don't see it like my back?
By the tires?
Something looked out or something?
I can't see it!
Are you sure?
I can't see him!
Ah!
Oh!
What the hell was that?
Oh my God!
Do you see him?
Did we hit him?
Look out the side of the window!
He's on the other side!
I'm almost!
My toes!
Will somebody get him and stop him?
Please help me!
Hurry!
We're dragging him!
Do you see him?
Where is he?
Is he there?
Do you see him?
Jack!
I see him!
What?
What do you do?
Is he okay?
He's alright!
What?
Hold my legs!
Somebody hold my legs!
Hold his legs!
Come on!
I got you!
Is he hurt?
Is he okay?
Hold his legs!
Hold!
Come on!
We got him now!
Jesus, I can't believe it!
You are a complete jerk!
You know that!
Oh, thank God!
Did you have any luck with the bomb?
Yeah, it didn't go off.
Ortiz, thanks.
How many lives you got, man?
You're not too bright, man.
But you got some big round hairy corners.
Thanks.
Very gross, Ortiz.
Can't even pay him a compliment.
How you doing?
Get the shit out of me, Jack!
Get the shit out!
Other than that, I'm fine.
What is that smell?
It's gas.
We're leaking gas?
We are now.
What, you felt you needed another challenge or something?
Mac.
Mac, here, go ahead.
Can you get a fuel truck to pace us here?
We're losing gas.
I'll see what I can find.
How much time?
I don't know, 10 minutes.
It doesn't look good.
Gotcha.
Norwood, get a fuel car out here on the double.
Is that gonna work?
I don't know.
Come on, Henry, save my life.
I'm sorry.
Harry?
You told me good news, man.
Oh, I'm sorry Jack.
He didn't make it.
Fuck!
It was the watch that led him to me, wasn't it?
Huh?
It seemed a little hammy to me to build the bomb out
of my precious retirement gift, but you know,
I figured a sign that said Howard Payne would be pushing it.
I'm going to rip your fucking spine out, I swear to God.
You're going to do exactly as you're told.
Jack, we both know that he was the brains
of your particular operation.
You can't beat me.
You're going to pay me every dollar.
Otherwise, you, the wildcat, and every innocent person
on that bus are going to end up just like your friend.
Are you paying attention?
Jack, are you listening to me?
Jack, Jack.
Yeah.
Good.
Now, you tell them that the drop point is Pershing Square.
There's a garbage can in the northeast corner.
You drop the bags and leave.
I don't show until all your people are gone.
It's getting on to 11 AM, Jack.
And I think it's going to be a very pretty day.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Jack.
God!
Jack, come on.
Get out of here!
Come on!
Don't give him any jacks!
Come on, please.
Jack, stop it!
Jack, come on.
Stop it, OK?
Don't give up on me right now, all right?
Come on.
And we're really scared, and we need you right now, all right?
I can't do this by myself.
Please?
Jack, please?
OK?
Please, all right?
We're going to die.
No, we're not.
We got this far, OK?
I'll be damned.
You go to the University of Arizona?
Yeah, so?
Good football team.
Yeah, I guess so.
I don't really know.
Arizona Wildcats.
Right?
He can see you.
What?
He can see me?
Just keep looking straight ahead.
He can see you.
He can see me?
Yes.
He called you a Wildcat before I didn't even pick up on it.
The bastard's got a camera right in your face.
He can see the whole bus.
He's been playing me for minute one.
Yeah, well, he can see me, but can he hear me?
Doesn't look like it.
He's just watching.
...is joining us.
Let me bring you up to speed.
The following is the story of a city bus rigged to explode if it slows down.
Races around literally in circles at the Los Angeles airport.
The two dead are a female passenger and the driver of another bus, both blown up by the
bomber.
And the other people in jeopardy are of course the passengers of the bus, held hostage at
the whim of a madman.
The whim of a madman.
I like that.
There's a camera on the bus just over my left shoulder.
I want you to stare straight ahead.
Don't make any big movements, OK?
It's Jack.
Yeah, I know about Harry.
Is that news van still around?
Get those cameras to stop taking.
Right.
LAPD, I need the suit in.
Now, you can broadcast your witch hunt, right?
There's a signal going to that bus, I want you to find it.
There's an interesting situation here.
We're going to have to take you off the air temporarily.
Yeah, sure.
Please, sir, stop taping.
Come on, come on, come on, hurry up.
Good, tape off of that.
Remember, no big movements.
Just look with.
That ain't going to be too hard.
Tape it, good, come on, tape it.
It's taping.
Jack.
Yeah.
Look.
Mac, fuel.
Yeah, Jack, five minutes.
Not enough time.
Run the tape, we have to unload.
I got it.
Not enough time, run the tape, we have to unload.
I only have a minute of tape.
Do it now.
I want you to make a tape and loop it so that it
runs over and over, OK?
All right, run it.
Run it!
All right, tape's rolling.
We still have no live picture, but the reports
are that the bus continues to circle inside LAX,
that everyone is safe for the moment.
It's hard to imagine what's going through their thoughts
at this time.
Certainly a sense of community.
Now the officer.
Bring the steering wheel and the gas pedal.
All right, let's get them off.
Just step on the clock.
OK, you, you, and you.
The police have just issued a general statement,
which really doesn't tell us much more
than all the papers do.
Grab my wrist, that's it, good.
Right ahead.
Come on, look straight ahead.
Come on, out your hand.
Come on.
The lock was stuck in your hand last night.
It's detached.
It's OK.
That's good.
Come on.
Grab my wrist and come across.
Put your hand down.
Take his hand.
Go down.
Come on.
That's it, you got it.
Hey, hey.
Come on.
All right, let's go.
Let's go.
Come on, buddy.
I got you.
Give me your hand.
Come on.
The hand.
Hold on.
Grab my hand.
I got you.
Come on.
Don't look down.
Just hold on.
Jack.
Hold these.
Grab my hand.
Come on.
All right.
Jack.
Jack, I can't hold this anymore.
Get out of here.
You, hold on.
Jesus, Jack.
No.
Hold it.
Jack.
Oh, God.
Put it down on the guy's pedal.
OK.
OK, I got it.
You got it?
I got it.
OK.
OK, Anna, get on.
God, I can't do this.
Jack, I can't do this.
Let's go.
Shit.
Jack.
Hold on.
Gotta make it big enough.
player wow
Shit!
Are you all right?
No.
It's okay.
It's okay, it's over.
It's over, I know you did it.
You did it.
Oh, fuck.
Oh, I hate the airport.
Yeah.
I'm not gonna get mushy on me, are you?
Maybe.
I think I might.
Hope not, because you know,
relationships that start under intense circumstances
they never last.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah, I've done extensive studying on this.
Here comes a cabal.
How you doing?
We're okay.
Well, I just might be a nice guy and let you have the rest of the day off.
So quiet.
Mac, this is Annie.
Annie, meet Lieutenant McMah.
We're good.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Annie McMah.
We're good.
Okay.
You should take care of it.
Ow!
Watch it.
Sorry.
We're gonna take you guys back and have you checked out.
Lieutenant!
It's him.
He wants to know when he's gonna get his money.
Son of a bitch, I can tell him what to do with his goddamn money.
He doesn't know it blew up.
30 minutes.
30 minutes later
We'll be right back.
All right, here's our target.
Fox?
Yes, sir.
You and four-one, you and one-two, you're in three.
Let's move it.
Norwood, are you sure the paint bomb is in with the money?
It's done, sir.
30 minutes later
We're gonna have to get our cameras to us.
We'll start making today.
Too bad, Jack, you could have made a good cop.
I'm sorry.
...a young woman in charge...
...and we will be reaching a report...
...on the landing field as soon as she gets set up.
The SWAT team has certainly...
...stinged themselves today as all of the patrolmen...
...who helped lead the bus out of the city.
It was potentially a disaster situation...
...and it's definitely been diffused to some extent.
There are still a number of bodies...
No!
No, no, no.
Hey!
Miss.
You can't be this close. You need to move back.
Oh, no, Jack Traven's here.
Jack Traven, yes. He asked that you be brought out of harm's way.
Just move right over here.
He's running a little late.
He's not late.
What?
He's never late.
Well, that money hasn't moved.
We got 200 eyes on that can.
A bird dog in the bag, I'd say he's covered.
Turn it on.
What for? It hasn't moved.
Just do it!
Shit, it's moving.
He's got the money.
Jack!
Shit!
Freeze!
Pop quiz, asshole.
You have a hair trigger aimed at your head.
What do you do?
Turn around.
Turn around!
Oh, no.
Sorry.
Be prepared.
It's the Boy Scout marching song.
What are you going to do, Jack?
I don't think you can shoot her.
Literally.
I'm going to shoot her.
Let her go.
No, I don't think I'm going to do that.
Fill it.
Now.
Well, I think Harry would be very disappointed
feeling that we're right back where we started, huh?
Let her go. You don't need her.
You have the money. Take it and walk.
Come on.
Just take it and walk. You don't need her.
Come on, just take it and go!
Stay right there!
I'll do it. I'll let go.
Oh, yeah.
You still don't get it,
do you, Jack?
The beauty of it.
A bomb is made to explode.
That's its meaning.
Its purpose.
Your life is empty because you spend it
trying to stop the bomb
from becoming.
And for who? For what?
Do you know what
a bomb is, Jack, that doesn't explode?
It is a cheap
gold watch, buddy.
You're crazy.
You're fucking crazy.
Oh, no.
Poor people are crazy, Jack.
I'm eccentric.
Get the money. Let's go.
Come on! Let's go! Move it! Move it!
You stay! Move it!
Move it! In the door!
In that door now!
Bye, Jack.
Punk.
All right!
Get in there!
Go on. Get in!
You get back in there!
You get this train moving! Go on!
Are these seats taken?
No, no.
Come on! Back over here!
Hands around the pole!
Come on!
Come on! Come on! Come on!
Please report Westbound 501.
What is your position?
Westbound 501, please check in.
Westbound 501.
In police orders to return to the station.
Westbound 501, do you copy?
You have to hold this.
It's like a grenade. You have to help me now.
Come on, hold it.
Don't let it go.
Huh?
Pounding on you.
Hey!
I'll take it from here.
No! No!
No!
Uh-oh! Uh-oh!
Wait, wait! Maybe you'd better let me have this after all.
I'm afraid you're a bit hysterical.
And you might let this go a mite early.
Hey! Hey!
Buckaroo!
It's not because you're a woman, all right?
Hey, it's all right.
Looks like we're all alone.
Look, you won.
Okay, you beat Jack. You beat everybody.
Just throw me on the train. I don't care, okay?
Okay. This stick, huh?
Works on a remote.
When you explode,
that's where they'll come. But that's not where I'll be.
I have a different plan.
A mess like that, they don't even
count body parts.
Gives me more time.
It's not gonna hurt any.
Hey, Jack!
Is that you?
He's so persistent, he always gets his man.
Wouldn't be able to interest you in a bribe, would I?
I've got the
plenty to go around!
My money!
I'm sorry.
You bastard!
How does that feel?
You want that?
You like it, you bastard?
My money!
Shit!
You!
I'm coming for you, Jack!
You're finished!
Hey, I'll drop the stick for you!
You want that?
I got you!
I'm here to get you!
Oh, yes!
What do you do, Jack?
What do you do? You're so smart, right?
You piece of shit!
I'm the guy with the plan,
because I'm smarter than you!
I'm smarter than you!
Yeah?
Well, I'm taller.
Jack!
Oh, God, I thought you were dead!
Turn around.
Where's Payne?
He lost his head.
Oh, God!
Let's take this off, shall we?
Yes, let's take this off.
Take it off.
Hello? Hello?
I need you to copy.
Jack, this is Mac.
Can you hear me?
I got your foot there.
You've got to stop the train.
The track isn't finished, I repeat.
The track is not finished.
Do you copy?
If someone can hear me...
Mac, can you hear me?
Try the emergency brake.
You need to copy.
That's it, you're...
It works!
Annie, you won't believe this.
We have to jump.
Can't stop it?
Willem, okay, Willem, do me and I'd love to go with you.
Come on, please.
I don't have a key.
What?
Oh, shit.
Shit!
No!
You've got to get off!
You've got to get off the train!
Jack, please!
This track is finished.
Come on, you've got to get off this train.
This is crazy.
There's a curb ahead.
I'm going to speed it up.
Make it jump the track.
This is really stupid.
Jack, please, you can still jump.
Jack, please, please.
I'm going to speed it up.
Okay.
Yeah, it's right here.
Oh, shit!
Holy shit!
What the hell is that?
What's that doing?
I can't believe he hit my van.
I'm real
He didn't leave me
He didn't get
He didn't believed me
Didn't have anything to be
It didn't have anything to be just that
I have to warn you.
I've heard relationships based on intense experiences never work.
Okay.
We'll have to base it on sex then.
Whatever you say, ma'am.
I'm sorry.